<problem display_name="Quiz 0" graded="true" rerandomize="onreset">
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 1:</h2>
  <p>Class <code>Customer</code> has a subclass <code>VIPCustomer</code>.  Assuming a well written program, which of the following statements are true? (More than one may be true.)</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <choiceresponse>
    <checkboxgroup>
      <choice correct="false">
        <text>Any method that takes an instance of <code>VIPCustomer</code> can safely be passed an instance of <code>Customer</code>.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="true">
        <text>Any method that takes an instance of <code>Customer</code> can safely be passed an instance of <code>VIPCustomer</code>.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="false">
        <text>The set of instance variables of a <code>VIPCustomer</code> must be the same as the set of instance variables of a <code>Customer</code>.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="true">
        <text>If you call a nonexistent method on a <code>VIPCustomer</code>, the call will still work if <code>Customer</code> implements that method.</text>
      </choice>
    </checkboxgroup>
  </choiceresponse>
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 2:</h2>
  <p>Which statement is ALWAYS true when an exception occurs in a modern programming language?</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <multiplechoiceresponse direction="vertical" randomize="yes">
    <choicegroup type="MultipleChoice">
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="1">
        <text>The program will immediately stop execution.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="true" name="2">
        <text>An immediate change of control flow occurs.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice location="bottom" correct="false" name="3">
        <text>An arithmetic operation was performed whose result is outside the range that the computer can represent.</text>
      </choice>
    </choicegroup>
  </multiplechoiceresponse>
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 3:</h2>
  <p>You're asked to write a program whose input is a text document of about 1 million words, and whose output is the number of times each word appears in the document.  Which of the following data structures would be most efficient for solving this problem?</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <multiplechoiceresponse direction="vertical" randomize="yes">
    <choicegroup type="MultipleChoice">
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="1">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>Array</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="true" name="2">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>Hash map or hash table</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="3">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>Linked list</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="bottom" correct="false" name="4">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>Tree</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
    </choicegroup>
  </multiplechoiceresponse>
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 4:</h2>
  <p>Performance data from a particular website shows that for 100 sampled requests, 90 were of type A and the remaining 10  were of type B. The 90 type A requests were completed in a total of 8ms. The 10 type B requests were completed in a total of 28ms. Which statement is TRUE regarding this distribution of latencies?</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <multiplechoiceresponse direction="vertical" randomize="yes">
    <choicegroup type="MultipleChoice">
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="1">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>The median request latency is higher than the mean request latency.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="true" name="2">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>The median request latency is lower than the mean request latency.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="3">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>The site always has lower throughput for type A requests than for type B requests.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="bottom" correct="false" name="4">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>The site always has lower throughput for type B requests than for type A requests.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
    </choicegroup>
  </multiplechoiceresponse>
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 5:</h2>
  <p>Which statements are true about the content of this class? (More than one may be true.)</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <choiceresponse>
    <checkboxgroup>
      <choice correct="false">
        <text> One reason to take the class is to get an official certificate from UC Berkeley</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="true">
        <text> You can either do the assignments by downloading Virtual Box and run the environment on your own computer or by using an preinstalled environment on AWS EC2.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="true">
        <text> This class is about principles of software engineering, and will teach how to build a SaaS app using the Agile lifecycle and a modern programming language and framework (Ruby on Rails).</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="true">
        <text> In the prior offering, about half of the students spent 1 to 6 hours per week on this class, while the other half typically spent 7 to 12 hours per week.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="false">
        <text> Since assignments are automatically graded, there is little programming in this course.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="false">
        <text> This course uses easier assignments than the on campus UC Berkeley course which it is based on.</text>
      </choice>
    </checkboxgroup>
  </choiceresponse>
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 6:</h2>
  <p>Which statements are true about textbooks for this class? (More than one may be true.)</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <choiceresponse>
    <checkboxgroup>
      <choice correct="false">
        <text>You must buy the book "Engineering Long-Lasting Software".</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="true">
        <text>The information described in the recommended textbooks are also available for free, with links to resources listed on the course info page.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="false">
        <text>Although the course is free, you must buy at least one book to take this class.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="false">
        <text>To read a Kindle version of a book, you must first buy a hardware Kindle reader.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="true">
        <text>Kindle Book Reader software also runs on Linux systems.</text>
      </choice>
    </checkboxgroup>
  </choiceresponse>
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 7:</h2>
  <p>Which statement is NOT part of the Agile Manifesto?</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <multiplechoiceresponse direction="vertical" randomize="yes">
    <choicegroup type="MultipleChoice">
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="1">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> We value individuals and interactions over processes and tools.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="true" name="2">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> We value self-organizing over managers.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="3">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> We value working software over comprehensive documentation.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="bottom" correct="false" name="4">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> We value customer collaboration over contract negotiation.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="bottom" correct="false" name="5">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> We value responding to change over following a plan.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
    </choicegroup>
  </multiplechoiceresponse>
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 8:</h2>
  <p>Service Oriented Architecture improves programmer productivity via which of the following?</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <multiplechoiceresponse direction="vertical" randomize="yes">
    <choicegroup type="MultipleChoice">
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="1">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> Conciseness.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="true" name="2">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> Reuse.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="3">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> Synthesis.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="bottom" correct="false" name="4">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> Automation and Tools.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
    </choicegroup>
  </multiplechoiceresponse>
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 9:</h2>
  <p>Which of the following explanations for Software as a Service's popularity is least accurate?</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <multiplechoiceresponse direction="vertical" randomize="yes">
    <choicegroup type="MultipleChoice">
      <choice correct="true" name="1">
        <text>Since the client software is usually deployed in the browser there are no compatibility issues for SaaS client software.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="false" name="2">
        <text>SaaS eliminates most installation problems caused by computer hardware capability or operating system version.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="false" name="3">
        <text>SaaS eliminates worries about data loss.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="false" name="4">
        <text>SaaS makes it easy for groups of people to interact with the same data.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="false" name="5">
        <text>If data is large or changes frequently, it is simpler to keep a single copy at central site.</text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="false" name="6">
        <text>A single copy of the software running on the controlled environment of a central computer reduces software development difficulties.
      </text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="false" name="7">
        <text>A single copy of the software running on the controlled environment of a central computer means upgrades are easier for SaaS developers.
      </text>
      </choice>
      <choice correct="false" name="8">
        <text>A single copy of the software running on the controlled environment of a central computer means no software upgrade requests for SaaS users.</text>
      </choice>
    </choicegroup>
  </multiplechoiceresponse>
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 10:</h2>
  <p>Which statement is NOT true about Cloud Computing?</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <multiplechoiceresponse direction="vertical" randomize="yes">
    <choicegroup type="MultipleChoice">
      <choice location="random" correct="true" name="1">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>Traditional datacenters are not as cost effective primarily because they buy different types of computers than those found in the cloud computing warehouses.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="2">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>Using many computers for a few hours costs the same amount as using a few computers for many hours.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="3">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>Cloud computing allows anybody to use the equivalent of one the 50 fastest computers in the world for less than $1000 per hour.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="bottom" correct="false" name="4">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>Cloud computing is based on clusters of commodity computers connected by commodity Ethernet switches.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
    </choicegroup>
  </multiplechoiceresponse>
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 11:</h2>
  <p>Which of the following is the course policy regarding submission of homework assignments after their due date?</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <multiplechoiceresponse direction="vertical" randomize="yes">
    <choicegroup type="MultipleChoice">
      <choice location="random" correct="true" name="1">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>Homework assignments submitted after the due date but less than seven days late late will receive a 25% penalty.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="2">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>There is no late penalty for homework assignments.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="3">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>Homework assignments submitted after the due date will receive zero points.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
    </choicegroup>
  </multiplechoiceresponse>
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 12:</h2>
  <p>Which of the following is the course policy for submitting quizzes?</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <multiplechoiceresponse direction="vertical" randomize="yes">
    <choicegroup type="MultipleChoice">
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="1">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>Quizzes turned in after the due date will receive a 25% penalty.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="2">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>There is no late penalty for quizzes.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="true" name="3">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span>Quizzes submitted after the due date will receive zero points.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
    </choicegroup>
  </multiplechoiceresponse>
  <startouttext/>
  <br/>
  <h2>Question 13:</h2>
  <p>Many HTML documents can reference the same CSS stylesheet. This best exemplifies which mechanism for enhancing productivity?</p>
  <endouttext/>
  <multiplechoiceresponse direction="vertical" randomize="yes">
    <choicegroup type="MultipleChoice">
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="1">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> Clarity via conciseness.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="true" name="2">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> Reuse.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="random" correct="false" name="3">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> Automation and tools.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
      <choice location="bottom" correct="false" name="4">
        <span>
          <text>
            <span> Synthesis.</span>
          </text>
        </span>
      </choice>
    </choicegroup>
  </multiplechoiceresponse>
</problem>
